Kenny Becerra Frontend Developer





About me

I am a software engineer with a passion for front-end development. I have 3-4 years experience in front-end development and my technical career has centered around building web applications using Vanilla JS, jQuery, React/Redux, and Ember (2.X.X). Checkout my github to see some of the Front-end dev projects I've worked on.



Skills

HTML/CSS

- ✓ HTML5
 ✓ CSS3
 ✓ SASS/LESS
 ✓ Flexbox
 ✓ CSS Grid
 ✓ Bootstrap

 JAVASCRIPT
- ✓ ES5/ES6 ✓ JQuery ✓ React / Redux ✓ Node.js
 TOOLS
- ✓ NPM
 ✓ Webpack
 ✓ Gulp
 ✓ VS Code
 ✓ Git



Work Experience

Frontend Developer at Inxeption

San Francisco, CA July 2019 - Present

Responsible for converting Adobe XD mockups into functional web pages utilizing React, Ember, and vanilla JavaScript.

Collaborated with product managers, designers, and backend engineers to resolve bugs and build new features in existing applications.

Built a development environment/toolset (using node.js, express, handlebars, and MJML) for developing cross email-client compatible templates for web app notifications and outreach.

Programmer Analyst at Pacific Gas & Electric

San Francisco, CA January 2017 - July 2019

Developed all User Interfaces for Third-Party Security (TSR) team vendor database using latest technologies for HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, Webpack, Babel, NPM, Jest .

Utilized Node.js libraries to automate team process and create tools to enhance email awareness campaigns, metrics tracking and reporting.

Developed Single Page Applications (SPAs) in Sharepoint using Semantic UI, jQuery, D3.js and chart.js for TSR team to access/modify backend database via Sharepoint REST Calls.

Perform ad-hoc frontend development requests for Cybersecurity crossteam collaboration and data access to TSR team backend.

Programmer Analyst at Pacific Gas & Electric

San Francisco, CA August 2015 - December 2016

Developed scripting solutions for Energy Procurement Support team ad-hoc requests.

Developed UI functionality for Energy Procurement System tools using SQL, and VBA.

Automated administrative tasks and workflows using VBA, python and SharePoint Rest API



Education

Bachelors of Science in Computer Engineering

Florida State University



Contact

kennybecerra.j@gmail.com

https://github.com/kennybecerra

n www.linkedin.com/in/kennybecerra/



https://www.kennybecerra.com